<reference anchor="RFC3385" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc3385">
  <front>
    <title>Internet Protocol Small Computer System Interface (iSCSI) Cyclic Redundancy Check (CRC)/Checksum Considerations</title>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC3385"/>
    <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="3385"/>
    <seriesInfo name="Legacy"/>
    <author initials="D." surname="Sheinwald" fullname="D. Sheinwald"/>
    <author initials="J." surname="Satran" fullname="J. Satran"/>
    <author initials="P." surname="Thaler" fullname="P. Thaler"/>
    <author initials="V." surname="Cavanna" fullname="V. Cavanna"/>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Publisher</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Series</organization>
    </author>
    <date month="September" year="2002"/>
    <keyword>error detection code</keyword>
    <abstract>
      <t>Cyclic redundancy check (CRC) codes [Peterson] are shortened 
cyclic codes used for error detection. A number of CRC codes have 
been adopted in standards: ATM, IEC, IEEE, CCITT, IBM-SDLC, and 
more [Baicheva].  The most important expectation from this kind 
of code is a very low probability for undetected errors.  The 
probability of undetected errors in such codes has been, and 
still is, subject to extensive studies that have included both 
analytical models and simulations. Those codes have been used 
extensively in communications and magnetic recording as they 
demonstrate good 'burst error' detection capabilities, but are 
also good at detecting several independent bit errors.  Hardware 
implementations are very simple and well known; their simplicity 
has made them popular with hardware developers for many years. 
However, algorithms and software for effective implementations of 
CRC are now also widely available [Williams]. 
The probability of undetected errors depends on the polynomial 
selected to generate the code, the error distribution (error 
model), and the data length. 
In this memo, we attempt to give some estimates for the 
probability of undetected errors to facilitate the selection of 
an error detection code for iSCSI.  
We will also attempt to compare CRCs with other checksum forms 
(Fletcher, Adler, weighted checksums), as permitted by available 
data.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>