<reference anchor="RFC.4707" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc4707">
  <front>
    <title>Netnews Administration System (NAS)</title>
    <author fullname="P. Grau" initials="P." surname="Grau">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="V. Heinau" initials="V." surname="Heinau">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="H. Schlichting" initials="H." surname="Schlichting">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="R. Schuettler" initials="R." surname="Schuettler">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Series</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2006" month="October"/>
    <abstract>
      <t>The Netnews Administration System (NAS) is a framework to simplify the administration and usage of network news (also known as Netnews) on the Internet. Data for the administration of newsgroups and hierarchies are kept in a distributed hierarchical database and are available through a client-server protocol.</t>
      <t>The database is accessible by news servers, news administrators, and news readers. News servers can update their configuration automatically; administrators are able to get the data manually. News reader programs are able to get certain information from an NAS server, automatically or at a user's discretion, which provides detailed information about groups and hierarchies to the user.</t>
      <t>NAS is usable in coexistence with the current, established process of control messages; an unwanted interference is impossible. Furthermore, NAS is able to reflect the somewhat chaotic structure of Usenet in a hierarchical database. NAS can be used without modification of existing news relay, news server, or news reader software; however, some tasks will be better accomplished with NAS-compliant software. This memo defines an Experimental Protocol for the Internet community.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC4707"/>
  <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="4707"/>
  <seriesInfo name="INDEPENDENT"/>
</reference>