<reference anchor="RFC.5863" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc5863">
  <front>
    <title>DomainKeys Identified Mail (DKIM) Development, Deployment, and Operations</title>
    <author fullname="T. Hansen" initials="T." surname="Hansen">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="E. Siegel" initials="E." surname="Siegel">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="P. Hallam-Baker" initials="P." surname="Hallam-Baker">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author fullname="D. Crocker" initials="D." surname="Crocker">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Series</organization>
    </author>
    <date year="2010" month="May"/>
    <workgroup>dkim</workgroup>
    <abstract>
      <t>DomainKeys Identified Mail (DKIM) allows an organization to claim responsibility for transmitting a message, in a way that can be validated by a recipient. The organization can be the author's, the originating sending site, an intermediary, or one of their agents. A message can contain multiple signatures, from the same or different organizations involved with the message. DKIM defines a domain-level digital signature authentication framework for email, using public key cryptography and using the domain name service as its key server technology. This permits verification of a responsible organization, as well as the integrity of the message content. DKIM will also provide a mechanism that permits potential email signers to publish information about their email signing practices; this will permit email receivers to make additional assessments about messages. DKIM's authentication of email identity can assist in the global control of "spam" and "phishing". This document provides implementation, deployment, operational, and migration considerations for DKIM. This document is not an Internet Standards Track specification; it is published for informational purposes.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC5863"/>
  <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="5863"/>
  <seriesInfo name="IETF"/>
</reference>