<reference anchor="IETF.RFC6252" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc6252">
  <front>
    <title>A Framework of Media-Independent Pre-Authentication (MPA) for Inter-Domain Handover Optimization</title>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC6252"/>
    <author fullname="A. Dutta"/>
    <author fullname="V. Fajardo"/>
    <author fullname="Y. Ohba"/>
    <author fullname="K. Taniuchi"/>
    <author fullname="H. Schulzrinne"/>
    <date year="2011" month="June" day="1"/>
    <keyword>Mobility</keyword>
    <keyword>Optimization</keyword>
    <keyword>Proactive handoff</keyword>
    <keyword>Link-layer security</keyword>
    <keyword>Handover taxonomy</keyword>
    <keyword>Layer 2 handoff</keyword>
    <keyword>Layer 3 handoff</keyword>
    <keyword>Network discovery</keyword>
    <keyword>Handover delay</keyword>
    <keyword>Packet loss</keyword>
    <keyword>Proactive binding update</keyword>
    <keyword>Multi-interface</keyword>
    <keyword>IP address acquisition</keyword>
    <keyword>Tunnel management</keyword>
    <abstract>This document describes Media-independent Pre-Authentication (MPA), a new handover optimization mechanism that addresses the issues on existing mobility management protocols and mobility optimization mechanisms to support inter-domain handover. MPA is a mobile- assisted, secure handover optimization scheme that works over any link layer and with any mobility management protocol, and is most applicable to supporting optimization during inter-domain handover. MPA's pre-authentication, pre-configuration, and proactive handover techniques allow many of the handoff-related operations to take place before the mobile node has moved to the new network. We describe the details of all the associated techniques and their applicability for different scenarios involving various mobility protocols during inter-domain handover. We have implemented the MPA mechanism for various network-layer and application-layer mobility protocols, and we report a summary of experimental performance results in this document. This document is a product of the IP Mobility Optimizations (MOBOPTS) Research Group. This document is not an Internet Standards Track specification; it is published for informational purposes.</abstract>
  </front>
</reference>