<reference anchor="RFC6373" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc6373">
  <front>
    <title>MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS-TP) Control Plane Framework</title>
    <author role="editor" fullname="L. Andersson" initials="L" surname="Andersson">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author role="editor" fullname="L. Berger" initials="L" surname="Berger">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author role="editor" fullname="L. Fang" initials="L" surname="Fang">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author role="editor" fullname="N. Bitar" initials="N" surname="Bitar">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <author role="editor" fullname="E. Gray" initials="E" surname="Gray">
      <organization/>
    </author>
    <date year="2011" month="September"/>
    <workgroup>ccamp</workgroup>
    <abstract>
      <t>The MPLS Transport Profile (MPLS-TP) supports static provisioning of transport paths via a Network Management System (NMS) and dynamic provisioning of transport paths via a control plane. This document provides the framework for MPLS-TP dynamic provisioning and covers control-plane addressing, routing, path computation, signaling, traffic engineering, and path recovery. MPLS-TP uses GMPLS as the control plane for MPLS-TP Label Switched Paths (LSPs). MPLS-TP also uses the pseudowire (PW) control plane for pseudowires. Management-plane functions are out of scope of this document.</t>
      <t>This document is a product of a joint Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF) / International Telecommunication Union Telecommunication Standardization Sector (ITU-T) effort to include an MPLS Transport Profile within the IETF MPLS and Pseudowire Emulation Edge-to-Edge (PWE3) architectures to support the capabilities and functionalities of a packet transport network as defined by the ITU-T.</t>
      <t>This document is not an Internet Standards Track specification; it is published for informational purposes.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
  <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC6373"/>
  <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="6373"/>
</reference>