<reference anchor="RFC9706" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc9706">
  <front>
    <title>TreeDN: Tree-Based Content Delivery Network (CDN) for Live Streaming to Mass Audiences</title>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC9706"/>
    <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="9706"/>
    <seriesInfo name="IETF"/>
    <author initials="L." surname="Giuliano" fullname="L. Giuliano"/>
    <author initials="C." surname="Lenart" fullname="C. Lenart"/>
    <author initials="R." surname="Adam" fullname="R. Adam"/>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Publisher</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Series</organization>
    </author>
    <date month="January" year="2025"></date>
    <workgroup>Media OPerationS</workgroup>
    <keyword>multicast</keyword>
    <keyword>SSM</keyword>
    <keyword>AMT</keyword>
    <keyword>LISP</keyword>
    <keyword>CDN</keyword>
    <keyword>PIM-SSM</keyword>
    <abstract>
      <t>&lt;p&gt;As Internet audience sizes for high-interest live events reach unprecedented levels and bitrates climb to support formats and applications such as 4K, 8K, and Augmented Reality (AR), live streaming can place a unique type of stress upon network resources.  TreeDN is a tree-based Content Delivery Network (CDN) architecture designed to address the distinctive scaling challenges of live streaming to mass audiences.  TreeDN enables operators to offer Replication-as-a-Service (RaaS) at a fraction of the cost of traditional, unicast-based CDNs -- in some cases, at no additional cost to the infrastructure.  In addition to efficiently utilizing network resources to deliver existing multi-destination traffic, this architecture also enables new types of content and use cases that previously were not possible or economically viable using traditional CDN approaches.  Finally, TreeDN is a decentralized architecture and a democratizing technology that makes content distribution more accessible to more people by dramatically reducing the costs of replication.&lt;/p&gt;</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>