<reference anchor="RFC9968" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc9968">
  <front>
    <title>Report from the IAB Workshop on the Next Era of Network Management Operations (NEMOPS)</title>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC9968"/>
    <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="9968"/>
    <seriesInfo name="IAB"/>
    <author initials="W." surname="Hardaker" fullname="W. Hardaker"/>
    <author initials="D." surname="Dhody" fullname="D. Dhody"/>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Publisher</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Series</organization>
    </author>
    <date month="May" year="2026"/>
    <keyword>YANG</keyword>
    <keyword>NETCONF</keyword>
    <keyword>RESTCONF</keyword>
    <keyword>NMOPS</keyword>
    <keyword>RFC3535</keyword>
    <abstract>
      <t>The "Next Era of Network Management Operations (NEMOPS)" workshop was convened by the Internet Architecture Board (IAB) from December 3-5, 2024 as a three-day online meeting. It builds on a previous 2002 workshop, the outcome of which was documented in RFC 3535, identifying 14 operator requirements for consideration in future network management protocol design and related data models, along with some recommendations for the IETF. Much has changed in the Internet's operation and technological foundations since then. The NEMOPS workshop reviewed the past outcomes and discussed any operational barriers that prevented these technologies from being widely implemented. With the industry, network operators and protocol engineers working in collaboration, the workshop developed a suggested plan of action and network management recommendations for the IETF and IRTF. Building on RFC 3535, this document provides the report of the follow-up IAB workshop on network management.</t>
      <t>Note that this document is a report on the proceedings of the workshop. The views and positions documented in this report are those of the workshop participants and do not necessarily reflect IAB views and positions.</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>