<reference anchor="RFC9920" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc9920">
  <front>
    <title>RFC Editor Model (Version 3)</title>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC9920"/>
    <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="9920"/>
    <seriesInfo name="Editorial"/>
    <author initials="P." surname="Hoffman" fullname="P. Hoffman"/>
    <author initials="A." surname="Rossi" fullname="A. Rossi"/>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Publisher</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Series</organization>
    </author>
    <date month="February" year="2026"></date>
    <keyword>RFC Series</keyword>
    <keyword>RFC Series Working Group</keyword>
    <keyword>RSWG</keyword>
    <keyword>RFC Production Center</keyword>
    <keyword>RPC</keyword>
    <abstract>
      <t>&lt;p&gt;This document specifies version 3 of the RFC Editor Model. The model defines two high-level tasks related to the RFC Series. First, policy definition is the joint responsibility of the RFC Series Working Group (RSWG), which produces policy proposals, and the RFC Series Approval Board (RSAB), which approves such proposals. Second, policy implementation is primarily the responsibility of the RFC Production Center (RPC) as contractually overseen by the IETF Administration Limited Liability Company (IETF LLC). In addition, various responsibilities of the RFC Editor function are now performed alone or in combination by the RSWG, RSAB, RPC, RFC Series Consulting Editor (RSCE), and IETF LLC. Finally, this document specifies the Editorial Stream for publication of future policy definition documents produced through the processes defined herein.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the publication of RFC 9280, lessons have been learned about implementing this model. This document lists some of those lessons learned and updates RFC 9280 based on that experience. This document obsoletes RFC 9280.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This document updates RFCs 7841, 7991, 7992, 7993, 7994, 7995, 7996, 7997, 8729, 8730, and 9720.&lt;/p&gt;</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>