<reference anchor="RFC9783" target="https://www.rfc-editor.org/info/rfc9783">
  <front>
    <title>Arm's Platform Security Architecture (PSA) Attestation Token</title>
    <seriesInfo name="DOI" value="10.17487/RFC9783"/>
    <seriesInfo name="RFC" value="9783"/>
    <seriesInfo name="INDEPENDENT"/>
    <author initials="H." surname="Tschofenig" fullname="H. Tschofenig"/>
    <author initials="S." surname="Frost" fullname="S. Frost"/>
    <author initials="M." surname="Brossard" fullname="M. Brossard"/>
    <author initials="A." surname="Shaw" fullname="A. Shaw"/>
    <author initials="T." surname="Fossati" fullname="T. Fossati"/>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Publisher</organization>
    </author>
    <author>
      <organization>RFC Series</organization>
    </author>
    <date month="June" year="2025"></date>
    <keyword>Remote Attestation</keyword>
    <keyword>EAT profile</keyword>
    <keyword>Evidence</keyword>
    <keyword>RATS</keyword>
    <keyword>IoT</keyword>
    <abstract>
      <t>&lt;p&gt;Arm's Platform Security Architecture (PSA) is a family of hardware and firmware security specifications, along with open-source reference implementations, aimed at helping device makers and chip manufacturers integrate best-practice security into their products. Devices that comply with PSA can generate attestation tokens as described in this document, which serve as the foundation for various protocols, including secure provisioning and network access control. This document specifies the structure and semantics of the PSA attestation token.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PSA attestation token is a profile of the Entity Attestation Token (EAT). This specification describes the claims used in an attestation token generated by PSA-compliant systems, how these claims are serialized for transmission, and how they are cryptographically protected.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This Informational document is published as an Independent Submission to improve interoperability with Arm's architecture. It is not a standard nor a product of the IETF.&lt;/p&gt;</t>
    </abstract>
  </front>
</reference>